American Song Sheets, 1850-1870 M1628.2.A5
Lilly Library
- 373. Sprig of Shillelah. - Och, love is the soul of a neat Irishman (4 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 374. Squire Jone's Daughter. - Sweet is the gush of waterfalls (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, 0c1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Wolf 2223a.
- 375. The Stage Driver. On the Knickerbocker Line. - Now white folks pay attention, Ise gwane to sing a song (3 verses.) Composed and sung by Unsworth. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Not in Wolf.
- 376. The Standard Bearer. - Upon the tented field a Minstrel Knight (3 verses and choruses.) New York: Andrew 5, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2235a.
- 377. The Standard Bearer. - Upon the tented field a Minstrel Knight (3 verses and choruses.) As sung by Mr. J. Spellman. Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2235b.
- 378. The Standard of the Free. National Song and Chorus. - Fling out that Banner, the Standard of the free (3 verses and chorus.) Dedicated to Col. Lefferts, and officers and men of the Gallant New-York Seventh Regiment.---Sung with great Applause at the Tammany Celebration, 4th July 1861. Words and Music by John Mahon. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship. Wolf 2236b.
- 379. Stand by the Flag. - Stand by the flag ye gallant sons (4 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2229b.
- 380. Stand to Your Guns! - Stand to your guns, my hearts of oak (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship. Wolf 2232a.
- 381. The Star of Love. - The star of love now shines above (2 verses and chorus.) Sung by N. W. Gould, at Bryants' Minstrels. New York: H. De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 382. Star of the Twilight! Beautiful Star! - Star of the twilight! Beautiful Star! (2 verses.) Second song: "To the Highlands." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 2239.
- 383. The Steam Arm. - Oh, wonders sure, will never cease (12 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2248.
- 384. Steph. A. Douglas and H. V. Johnson. - We'll raise our glorious banner high (3 verses.) Air: "Dandy Jim of Caroline." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship. See Wolf 2249.
- 385. The Strawberry Girl. - With this humble stock to store (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 386. Sunlight on the Sea. - Sunshine on the wave is lying (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 2260.
- 387. The Sunny Hours of Childhood. - The sunny, sunny hours of childhood (2 verses.) Second song: "Land of the Brave and Free." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Not in Wolf.
- 388. Sweep O! - I come from old Louisiana (4 verses.) Sung by the Original Virginia Serenaders. Air - "Buy a Broom." Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2265.
- 389. Sweet Bolt Ben Allis. - 0 don't you remember, Sweet Bolt Ben Allis (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 390. Sweet Evelina. - Way down in the meadow where the lily first blows (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. See Wolf 2267.
- 391. A Sweet Face at the Window. - A sweet face at the window (3 verses and chorus.) Words by W. C. Baker. Music by H.P. Danks. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 2268.
- 392. Sweet Jenny of the Moor. - One morn, for recreation, as I strayed by the sea-side (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. See Wolf 2271.
- 393. Sweet Lilies of the Valley. - O'er barren hills and flowery dales (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 394. Taken in and Done For. - One day, I strolled out West, round every street went dodging (7 verses.) Air - "Down in Piccadilly." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 2283.
- 395. That's Where the Laugh Comes In. - Augustus Don Pedro, a handsome young man (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 2310.
- 396. There Is Light Beyond the River. - There is light beyond the river (5 verses and chorus.) No.945. N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 397. There's a Light in the Window for Thee. - There's a light in the window for thee, brother (4 verses and chorus.) With narrative preceding text, beginning: "When a boy but twelve years old...." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Not in Wolf.
- 398. There's a Queer Time Coming, Boys. - There's a queer time coming boys-a queer time coming (6 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 399. A Thousand a Year. Robin Ruff and Gaffer Green. - If I had a thousand a year, Gaffer Green (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Not in Wolf.
- 400. Three Bells. - Come swell the strain, the proud refrain (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 401. Thy Voice Hath a Charm. - Thy voice hath a charm, Thy smile hath a spell (2 verses.) Words and Music by Lucas Brinley. Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2332.
- 402. 'Tis Home Where the Heart Is. - "Tis home where e'er the heart is (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 2341 a.
- 403. 'Tis Midnight Hour. - 'Tis midnight hour, the moon shines bright (2 verses.) Second song: "Oft in the Stilly Night." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments. See Wolf 2342.
- 404. 'Tis Said that Absence Conquers Love. - 'Tis said that absence conquers love (4 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2343 a.
- 405. To the West. - To the West! to the West! to the land of the free (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. See Wolf 2354.
- 406. A Tough Yarn. - Ladies and gents, if you will list a little while to me (8 verses.) Air -"Wonderful Crocodile." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. See Wolf 2360.
- 407. 'Twas Within a Mile of Edonburg Town. - 'Twas within a mile of Edinburgh town (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. See Wolf 2377.
- 408. The Two Lovers. - There was and old woman who somewhere did dwell (10 verses.) A highly romantic Song, to the tune of Vilikins and his Dinah. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2382a.
- 409. Uncle Sam's Farm. - Of all the mighty Nations, in the East or in the West (5 verses and chorus.) Tune - "Walk in de Parlor and Hear de Banjo Play. '9 New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2394a.
- 410. Under the Gaslight. Or Poor Little Laura. - Under the gas-light, while the snow falls (3 verses.) Words by Geo. Cooper. Music by Henry Tucker. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 2399.
- 411. Vengeons la Patrie. - Debout, Fils de l'Union (4 verses.) Hymne patriotique par Gustave Dime, ouvrier-estampeur. Air - "Gloire aux martyrs victorieux!" New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle, colored. Wolf 2450.
- 412. Victory at Last. - For many years we've waited (3 verses and chorus.) Words by Mrs. M. A. Kidder. Music by Wm. B. Bradley. New York: Chas. Magnus, n.d. Letter paper, blue ink. Headpiece: Magnus 62a?, colored. Wolf 2460h?.
- 413. The Village-Born Beauty. - See the star-breasted villain to yonder cot bound (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Not in Wolf.
- 414. Viva l'America. - Noble Republic! happiest of lands (3 verses and chorus.) Words and music by H. Millard. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle. See Wolf 2465.
- 415. Vive la Compagnie. - Let Bacchus to Venus libations pour forth (5 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper. See Wolf 2466.
- 416. The Vorkhouse Boy. - The cloth vos laid in the vorkhouse hall (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 417. Walk in the Parlor. - I'm right from old Virginny, with my head so full of knarledge (4 verses and chorus.) Second song: "Walkey in de Parlor." New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 418. The Wanderer's Farewell. - Farewell, dear friends, once more farewe11(2 verses and chorus.) As Sung by Dick McGowan, Banjoist and Comedian. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 2484a.
- 419. The Watchman. No.2. - The snow was falling fast and deep, and cold the North-wind swept (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2502.
- 420. The Waterford Boys. - Well, boys, for divarsion, we've all met together (6 verses and chorus.) Sung by Wm. Carleton. Air - "The Flaming O'Hannigans." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.
- 421. The Watery Grave. - The sun had set in its crimson bed (3 verses.) Composed by A.B.E. Second song: "Nellie, Wilt Thou Be My Bride." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2505.
- 422. We Are All So Fond of Kissing. - Oh, kiss me quick and let me go (3 verses and chorus.) As sung by John Dudley of Perham's Opera Troupe. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Not in Wolf.
- 423. The Wearing of the Green. - They've trampled on poor ould Ireland (5 verses.) Sung by J. H. Glenny, the celebrated Irish Comedian and Vocalist in the drama of "Arra na Pogue" at Niblo's Garden, New-York. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2526.
- 424. Weep not, Comrades, for Me. Weep not, oh, weep not! Comrades for me (3 verses and chorus.) And extract from soldier's diary. Words and Music by Geo. Reed Cromwell. New York: Charles Magnus, n.d. Letter paper, blue ink. Headpiece: Magnus 192, colored. Wolf 2529b.
- 425. Welcome Mother. - Welcome, mother! now I greet thee (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 2535a.
- 426. A Welcome to James Stephens. - All hail to Jimmy Stephens (8 verses.) By Michael O'Donnell. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 2539.
- 427. We Shall See Her No More. - Oh, the bright sunny South where the sugar cane grows (2 verses and chorus.) Words by C. Hart, music by F. Buckley. Sung with Tremendous Applause by Buckley's celebrated Band of Minstrels. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2521.
- 428. What Norah Said. A Reply to Norah O'Neal. - Is it lonely ye are then without me? (3 verses and 2 choruses.) Words by Arthur Matthison. Music by W. F. Wellman, Jr. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 2562a.
- 429. What Other Name than Thine, Mother. - What other name than thine, mother (4 verses and 2 choruses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Wolf 2563.
- 430. When I Am on a Distant Shore. - When l am on a distant shore (4 verses.) No.1119. Air - "The Harp That Once through Tara's Hall," by M. J. Million. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley Ethiopian. Wolf 256.
- 431. When I Dream that You Love Me. - When I dream that I love you, you 'ii surely forgive (3 verses.) Second song: "Angel of Light." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. See Wolf 2569.
- 432. When I Saw Sweet Nellie Home. - In the sky the bright stars glittered (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. See Wolf 2570.
- 433. When the Boys Come Home. - The boys are coming home again (3 verses and chorus.) Words and Music by Charles Carroll Sawyer. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2577.
- 434. When the Twilight Dews Are Failing. - When the twilight dews are falling soft (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan harp, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 435. Where Is My Lover? - Where is my lover? can any one tell? (3 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2594.
- 436. Where's That Back Pay? - Boys, our back pay is a coming (4 verses.) By J. Ward Childs, 53d. Massachusett's Reg. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 2599.
- 437. Where There's a Will, There's a Way. - This life is a difficult riddle (4 verses and chorus.) Sung by the celebrated Charles Vivian, at Butler's American Theatre.... New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Not in Wolf.
- 438. While There's Life, There's Hope. - Never lose heart, where 'er thou art (2 verses and 2 choruses.) As sung by Mr. John Collins, the celebrated Irish Comedian and Vocalist, in Brougham's play of the: Duke's Motto, at Niblo's Garden, N.Y. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 2601a.
- 439. Whispering Hope. - Soft as the voice of an angel (2 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Not in Wolf.
- 440. The Whistling Thief. - When Pat came o'er the hills his colleen fair to see (5 verses and moral.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 2603.
- 441. The White Pilgrim. - I came to the spot where the white pilgrim lay (14 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 442. Who Stole the Ham? - We had a ham, 'twas in the bunkroom hanging (2 verses, solo and chorus.) Air - "Virginia Rosebud." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 2613a.
- 443. Who Will care for Mother Now. - Why am I weak and weary? (3 verses and chorus.) Words by Chas. Carroll Sawyer, Music by Chas. F. Thompson. With narrative preceding text, beginning: "During one of our late battles...." N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2616.
- 444. Why Awa' So Lang at Night. - John, Anderson, my Jo, John (4 verses.) Air.- "John, Anderson, My Jo." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 2625.
- 445. Why Don't They Do So Now? - When I was a little boy, the ladies all would say (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Not in Wolf.
- 446. Widow Widdle. Or a Thousand Pounds a Year. - I once was dressy, volatile, and rich as any Jew (10 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2637a.
- 447. The Widow's Last Prayer. - Oh! Mother dear, leave off crying (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 2638.
- 448. The Wife's Lament. A New Temperance Song. - My Connor was loving, gentle and kind (5 verses and 2 choruses.) By Archibald Scott. Air - "Dear Irish Boy." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Wolf 2641.
- 449. Will Friendship Buy Us Bread. - Mother! she spoke of friendship; what did the lady mean? (4 verses.) By Wm. Shires. With a three-line narrative. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2645.
- 450. William of the Ferry. - Near Clyde's gay stream there liv'd a maid (4 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2651.
- 451. Willie Gray. Or Answer to Kitty Clyde. - Oh! who has not see Willie Gray (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.
- 452. Willie's Welcome Home. Answer to Willie, We Have Missed You. - Yes, Annie dear, my lov'd one (3 verses.) Words by A. Fleetwood. Music by A. Von Smit. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 2656.
- 453. Will They Weep for Me at Home. - Will they weep for me at home (3 verses.) Air - "Do They Think of Me at Home" - by Walter Warren. No.850. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2647d.
- 454. Woodman, Spare That Tree. - Woodman, spare that tree! (4 verses.) No.213. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley kissing cupids. Not in Wolf.
- 455. Woodman, Spare That Tree. - Woodman, spare that tree! (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. Not in Wolf.
- 456. Yankee Doodle Uncle Sam. - I'm Yankee-doodle Uncle Sam (8 verses and chorus.) As sung by Tony Pastor, also by D. McConhay. Tune.- "Bag of Nails." Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Wolf 2688.
- 457. The Yellow-Hair'd Laddie. - In April, when the primroses paint the sweet plain (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 458. Ye Winged Winds. - Tell me, ye winged winds, that round my pathway roar (4 verses and 2 choruses.) Sung by T. B. Prendergast, at Bryants' Minstrels. New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 459. You Would Not Leave Your Norah! - "You would not leave your Norah! (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2707.